Guide to the UE National Office Records Relating to District 9 and District 9 Locals, 1936-1990s UE.4.1.9
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- District 9 Locals, 2.
  - Local 1005
    - Local 1005 Organizational Attempt, June 22, 1937-December 21, 1938 (Box 8, Folder 110)
      - Vance Runyon to James Carey, June 22, 1937; 1.
      - Carey to Runyon, June 24, 1937; 2.
      - Julius Emspak to James Pascoe, December 21, 1938; 3.
      - Strike Settlement Proposal, 4.
  - Local 1007
    - Local 1007 Charter Application, August 4, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 111)
  - Local 1008
    - Local 1008 Correspondence and Application, August 3-November 12, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 112)
      - Charter Application, August 3, 1937; 1.
      - Albert Stonkus to Richard Cawley, November 12, 1937; 2.
  - Local 112F
    - Local 112F Officers Lists, January 23, 1950-February 16, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 113)
    - Local 112F Incoming Correspondence, April 13, 1950-October 17, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 114)
      - Julius Emspak to Joseph Levey Regarding Finances, April 13, 1950; 1.
      - Emspak to Levey Regarding Per Capita, May 5, 1950; 2.
      - James Matles to Ray Nichols, October 23, 1951; 3.
      - Matles Telegram to Nichols Regarding Finances, November 1, 1951; 4.
      - Matles to Nichols Regarding Per Capita, November 1, 1951; 5.
      - David Ratner to William Nichols Regarding Finances, October 17, 1952; 6.
    - Local 112F Outgoing Correspondence, April 10, 1950-October 29, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 115)
      - Henry Hall Telegram to James Matles Regaring Race Baiting, Factionalism and Officers, December 3, 1950; 1.
      - Leo Kochendofer to Emspak Regarding Per Capita and United Auto Workers Inter-union Rivalry, September 7, 1951; 2.
      - Joseph Levey to Emspak Regarding Per Capita, April 10, 1950; 3.
      - Levey to Emspak Regarding Finances, April 27, 1950; 4.
      - Ray Nichols to Matles Regarding United Auto Workers Inter-union Rivalry, October 17, 1951; 5.
      - Nichols to Matles Regarding Finances and United Auto Workers Inter-union Rivalry, October 29, 1951; 6.
    - Local 112F Disbanding and Finances, October 12, 1951-February 19, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 116)
      - Milt Burns Telegram to James Matles, October 12, 1951; 1.
      - Matles to Burns, October 24, 1951; 2.
      - H. J. Wierston to Emspak, November 6, 1951; 3.
      - Matles to John Gojack, January 23, 1952; 4.
      - Gojack to Matles, January 31, 1952; 5.
      - David Ratner to David Scribner, February 19, 1952; 6.
    - Local 112F Correspondence and Strike Results, January 23, 1950-September 28, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 117)
      - E. E. Smith to James Matles Regarding Inter-union Rivalry, January 23, 1950; 1.
      - Officers to Matles Regarding Contracts Regarding Factionalism, September 7, 1950; 2.
      - John Shaffer Telegram to Matles Regarding Contracts, October 2, 1950; 3.
      - Emspak Lettter Regarding Negotiations, November 9, 1950; 4.
      - David Ratner Memo to David Scribner, September 28, 1951; 5.
      - Strike Vote Results, 6.
  - Local 118F
    - Local 118F Officers Lists, November 1, 1949-December 30, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 118)
    - Local 118F Incoming Correspondence, January 23, 1951-April 17, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 119)
      - Larry Cover to Ed Prather Regarding Strikes, November 25, 1952; 1.
      - Julius Emspak to Stanley Goddard Regarding Per Capita and Strikes, January 23, 1951; 2.
      - Emspak to Nathan Anderson Regarding Lockouts, November 15, 1951; 3.
      - Emspak to Anderson Regarding Haynes Track Strikes, November 26, 1951; 4.
      - Emspak to Anderson Regarding Strikes, October 7-November 21, 1952; 5-12.
      - Emspak to David Winburn Regarding Strikes, April 17, 1953; 13.
      - James Matles to Winburn Regarding Finances, February 25-April 17, 1953; 14-16.
    - Local 118F Outgoing Correspondence, October 4, 1950-October 5, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 120)
      - Nathan Anderson to UE Regarding Haynes Track Strikes, January 1952; 1.
      - Robert Demps Telegram to Albert Fitzgerald Regarding Inter-union Rivalry, June 29, 1954; 2.
      - Stanley Gabbard to Julius Emspak Regarding Per Capita and Strikes, January 17, 1951; 3.
      - Paul Harter to Emspak Regarding Per Capita, October 4, 1950; 4.
      - Harter to James Matles Regarding Strikes, November 19, 1952; 5.
      - Harter to Ernest DeMaio Regarding Strikes, November 19, 1952; 6.
      - Edward Prather Telegram to Matles Regarding International Harvester Strikes and Firings, December 12, 1952; 7.
      - David Winburn to Matles Regarding Strikes with Bills, March 2, 1953; 8.
      - Winburn to Matles Regarding Finances, March 16, 1953; 9.
      - Winburn to John McCaffrey Regarding Firings, Race Baiting and United Auto Workers Inter-union Rivalry with September 30, 1951, L. J. Jewett Letter to Carl Henderson, October 5, 1954; 10.
    - Local 118F Publications, October 17, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 121)
      - "Violations of Civil Rights" Pamphlet Regarding Strikes with Edward Prather Letter to James Murray, October 17, 1952; 1.
    - Local 118F Per Capita, June 26-November 10, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 122)
      - Dick Marhanka to David Ratner, June 26, 1950; 1.
      - John Gojack to Ray Klausner, October 13, 1950; 2.
      - Julius Emspak to Gojack, November 10, 1950; 3.
    - Local 118F Strikes, June 26-December 16, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 123)
      - James Matles to John Gojack, September 5, 1952; 1.
      - Matles to Rita Kochert, December 16, 1952; 2.
      - Dick Marhanka to Dave Ratner, June 26, 1952; 3.
      - Gojack to Ray Klausner, October 13, 1952; 4.
      - Gojack to Matles, November 5, 1952; 5.
      - Matles to Gojck with Memo, November 7, 1952; 6.
      - Julius Emspak to Gojack, November 10, 1952; 7.
      - Gojack to Matles, November 10, 1952; 8.
    - Local 118F United Auto Workers Inter-union Rivalry, January 7-25, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 124)
      - James Matles to Alfred Smith, January 7, 1953; 1.
      - Report on International Harvester Election, January 25, 1953; 2.
    - Local 118F Financial Problems, March 8, 1954-January 21, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 125)
      - Emma Memo to Dave Ratner, March 8, 1954; 1.
      - John Gojack to James Matles with Gojack Letter to Robert Demps, March 15, 1954; 2.
      - Matles Memo to Janet, January 21, 1955; 3.
    - Local 118F Correspondence, December 4, 1949-April 9, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 126)
      - John Gojack Excerpt Regarding United Auto Workers Inter-union Rivalry, December 4, 1949; 1.
      - Gojack to Oliver Switzer Regarding Strikes, March 26, 1951; 2.
      - Elizabeth Moore to Julius Emspak Regarding Hayes Track Strikes, November 10, 1951; 3.
      - James Matles to Alfred Smith Regarding Finances, February 25, 1953; 4.
      - Smith to Matles Regarding Negotiations with Note, April 9, 1953; 5.
  - Local 119F
    - Local 119F Officers Lists, November 1, 1949-November 14, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 127)
    - Local 119F Incoming Correspondence, January 23, 1951-June 22, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 128)
      - Julius Emspak to Edwin Wolfe Regarding Per Capita, January 23, 1951; 1.
      - Emspak to Wolfe Regarding National Strike Fund, October 30, 1952; 2.
      - Emspak to Paul Swanson Regarding Dues, March 2, 1955; 3.
      - Emspak to Swanson Regarding United Auto Workers Inter-union Rivalry, June 22, 1955; 4.
      - John Gojack to Leslie Job Regarding Staff Members, December 26, 1952; 5.
      - James Matles to Eldon Mocherman Regarding Staff Members, March 21, 1952; 6.
      - Matles to Job Regarding Arbitration and Staff Members, March 23, 1953; 7.
      - Matles to Swanson Regarding United Auto Workers Inter-union Rivalry, May 9, 1955; 8.
    - Local 119F Outgoing Correspondence, January 20, 1951-June 21, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 129)
      - Winford Allen to James Matles Regarding Staff Members and Arbitration, March 3, 1953; 1-2.
      - Allen to Matles Regarding Teamsters Inter-union Rivalry, March 10-April 27, 1954; 3-4.
      - Leslie Job to Matles Regarding Arbitration, December 1953; 5.
      - Eldon Mocherman to Matles Regarding Staff Members, March 6, 1952; 6.
      - Paul Swanson to Julius Emspak Regarding Dues, February 22, 1955; 7.
      - Swanson to Matles Regarding United Auto Workers Inter-union Rivalry with May 1955, Swanson Letter to Pat Greathouse, May 3, 1955; 8.
      - Swanson to Matles Regarding United Auto Workers Inter-union Rivalry, June 2, 1955; 9.
      - Swanson to Matles Regarding Labor Unity and Inter-union Rivalry with June 15, 1955, Swanson Letter to UE, June 21, 1955; 10.
      - Edwin Wolfe to Emspak, January 20, 1951; 11.
    - Local 119F Leaflets, November 22, 1949 (Box 8, Folder 130)
      - Elmer Drake to Local 119F Members Regarding Officers and Factionalism, November 22, 1949; 1.
      - "It's UE all the Way" Regarding Inter-union Rivalry, 2.
    - Local 119F Arbitration Case, March 9, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 131)
      - John Gojack to Jim Shields, March 9, 1953; 1.
      - James Matles to Frank Allen, March 9, 1953; 2.
    - Local 119F American Federation of Labor Inter-union Rivalry, April 14-May 17, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 132)
      - Memo, April 14, 1954; 1.
      - John Gojack to James Matles, April 22, 1954; 2.
      - Matles to John Gojack, May 3, 1954; 3.
      - Gojack to Matles, May 11, 1954; 4.
      - Matles to Gojack, May 17, 1954; 5.
    - Local 119F United Auto Workers Financial Settlement, March 9-October 23, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 133)
      - John Gojack to Albert Fitzgerald, March 9, 1956; 1.
      - David Rothstein to Arthur Kinoy with Letter to First National Bank, October 18, 1956; 2.
      - Fitzgerald to First National Bank, October 23, 1956; 3.
    - Local 119F Correspondence, February 8, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 134)
      - Emma Memo to David Ratner Regarding Finances, February 8, 1954; 1.
  - Local 145F
    - Local 145F Officers Lists, November 1949-February 1955 (Box 8, Folder 135)
  - Local 153F
    - Local 153F Officers Lists, March 9, 1950-August 24, 1951 (Box 8, Folder 136)
  - Local 173F
    - Local 173F Incoming Correspondence, December 14, 1951-January 12, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 137)
      - Julius Emspak to Lovella Brightly Regarding National Strike Fund, October 24, 1952; 1.
      - Emspak to Earl Cole Regarding Per Capita, January 12, 1956; 2.
      - Albert Fitzgerald Regarding Ray Nicholson Regarding Negotiations, December 14, 1951; 3.
      - James Matles to Lawrence Draves Regarding Staff Members, March 21, 1952; 4.
    - Local 173F Outgoing Correspondence, November 19, 1951-January 4, 1956 (Box 8, Folder 138)
      - Earl Cole to Julius Emspak Regarding Per Capita, January 4, 1956; 1.
      - Thurl Gordon to Albert Fitzgerald Regarding Strikes, June 1, 1955; 2.
      - Ray Nicholson to Fitzgerald Regarding Dues and Negotiations, November 19, 1951; 3.
  - Local 236F
    - Local 236F Officers Lists, January 11-August 18, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 139)
    - Local 236F Outgoing Correspondence, November 23, 1949-October 2, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 140)
      - Thomas Delong to James Matles Regarding United Auto Workers Inter-union Rivalry, Firings and Seniority, November 23, 1949; 1.
      - Delong to Albert Fitzgerald Regarding Officers, August 17, 1950; 2.
      - Delong Telegram to General Executive Board Regarding District Jurisdiction, September 21, 1950; 3.
      - Winfrey Duncan to Julius Emspak Regarding Dues and Veterans, February 15, 1950; 4.
      - Duncan to Emspak Regarding Finances, May 4, 1950; 5.
      - Duncan to Emspak Regarding Strikes, October 2, 1950; 6.
      - Carl Keithly to John Gojack Regarding District Officers, February 7, 1950; 7.
    - Local 236F Publications, July 18, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 141)
      - Pamphlet Regarding Grievances and Firings, July 18, 1950; 1.
    - Local 236F Finances, April 20-25, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 142)
      - Grant Oakes to John Gojack with Bill, April 20, 1950; 1.
      - Gojack to Oakes with Memo, April 25, 1950; 2.
    - Local 236F General Executive Board Action, September 22, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 143)
      - General Executive Board Action Regarding District 7 Transfer, September 22, 1950; 1.